<resources>
    <string name="app_name">News</string>

<string name="content_1">MANILA (UPDATED) — Severe Tropical Storm Julian further intensified before noon on Sunday, threatening northern Luzon areas with strong winds, towering waves, and intense rains that could trigger landslides and floods, the state weather agency said.Batanes, the lightly populated province located at the nation northernmost tip, and the Babuyan Islands are particularly forecast to bear the brunt of the extreme weather conditions caused by Julian, which could still strengthen into a super typhoon.</string>
    <string name="content_2">MANILA – The repatriation of over a dozen Filipinos in conflict-hit Lebanon has been rescheduled to October 3, a Department of Migrant Workers (DMW) official said on Saturday.

They were supposed to be flown back home last September 26, but several international airlines temporarily suspended their flights as the tension between Israel and the Lebanese Hezbollah militia escalated.

"Hopefully, we are praying na on October 3, yung ating mga Filipinos na na-schedule nung September 26 ay makakarating na. Na-schedule na natin yan dahil nabalitaan nga namin na magli-lift na daw ng suspension, barring unforeseen circumstances," said DMW Officer-in-Charge and Undersecretary Felicitas Bay during a media forum in Quezon City.

Bay added that they are also arranging two more repatriation flights. According to the DMW, more than 500 Filipinos in Lebanon, along with their dependents, have already been brought home since October of last year. Of that number, 430 are Overseas Filipino Workers (OFW).

Bay hopes more Filipinos will take advantage of the voluntary repatriation program, saying that the government is prepared to assist them as they adjust to life back in the Philippines.

She said they will receive a total of P150,000 in financial assistance from the DMW and the Overseas Workers Welfare Administration.

"Meron din tayong measures or assistance coming from the DSWD, yung psychosocial counseling, at the same time, sa TESDA meron silang mga training vouchers," added Bay.

But for those who will choose to stay in Lebanon, Bay said they may seek the help of the Philippine embassy in Beirut and the Migrant Workers Office there, especially those living in the southern part of Lebanon.

"Most of the tension ay nagaganap sa south of Lebanon. Yung mga kababayan natin na andoon, hinihikayat ng ating Migrant Workers Office at ng embahada na magsilikas na sila. Meron tayong mga shelters na maaari silang manatili muna temporarily until such time na safe na," said Bay.
</string>

    <string name="content_3">MANILA – The revelation of a “discarded Chinese spy” imprisoned in Thailand linking dismissed Bamban Mayor Alice Guo to Chinese espionage operations in the Philippines is a “lead” that security agents need to investigate, a Department of Justice (DOJ) official said on Sunday.\n\n“It is… a serious indication that the security apparatus of our government should take a serious look at it,” Justice Undersecretary Raul Vasquez said in an interview with dzBB.\n\nThe disclosure emerged during Friday’s inquiry by the House of Representatives’ quad committee, which scrutinized Guo after an Al Jazeera documentary was shown about She Zhijiang, a jailed Chinese tycoon.\n\nREAD: Agitated? Alice Guo loses cool after House shows docu on Chinese spy\n\nHe claimed to have a dossier confirming the presence of Chinese spies, which included Guo’s Chinese name, “Guo Hua Ping.”\n\nWhile the DOJ has not yet received formal information regarding She’s allegations, Vasquez said that the agency believed issues surrounding Guo raise national security concerns that warrant investigation. “We cannot dismiss the possibility of that due to the mysterious questions and issues surrounding the character of former Mayor Alice Guo,” Vasquez said.</string>
    <string name="content_4">The militaries of the Philippines, Australia, Japan, New Zealand and the United States are holding joint maritime drills in the Philippines Exclusive Economic Zone on Saturday, Gen. Romeo Brawner Jr., chief of the Armed Forces of the Philippines, said.\n\nIn a statement Saturday, Brawner said the Multilateral Maritime Cooperative Activity involves naval and air force units of the participating countries and "demonstrates a collective commitment to strengthen regional and international cooperation in support of a free and open Indo-Pacific." The AFP chief did not give details of participating units, but the Australian defense ministry said in a release that HMAS Sydney and a Royal Australian Air Force P-8A Poseidon maritime patrol aircraft are joining the exercise, "enhancing cooperation and interoperability between our armed forces." The Philippines has been increasing training engagements with foreign partners and upgrading its defense agreements with them — it signed an agreement in July to allow Japanese troops access to the Philippines, and vice versa — in the face of increasingly aggressive moves by China in the West Philippine Sea.\n\nChina has ignored a 2016 arbitral ruling invalidating its sweeping claims over the South China Sea — part of which is the West Philippine Sea — and blames tension in the area on the Philippines and on the United States and other Western nations.\n\nCountries participating in the multilateral "cooperative activity" have raised concerns about Chinese actions in the West Philippine Sea, which has included the use of water cannons, aggressive maneuvers, and the deliberate ramming of Philippine Coast Guard ships. CHINESE AGGRESSIVENESS IN WEST PHILIPPINE SEA\n\nThe Philippine Coast Guard earlier this week was monitoring the presence of a Chinese research vessel and its six maritime militia escorts in the West Philippine Sea near Palawan in what an American analyst called a "survey in force."</string>
    <string name="headline1">Tropical Storm Julian Approaches</string>
    <string name="headline2">Repatriation of Filipinos from Lebanon</string>
    <string name="headline3">Controversy Surrounds Dismissed Mayor</string>
    <string name="headline4">Philippines Holds Joint Military Drills</string>

</resources>
